Luong-Ha Nguyen

Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning Engineer

Experienced AI/ML Engineer with a background in developing and optimizing learning paradigms as well as AI/ML pipelines, including modeling, validation, and deployment strategies on cloud platforms. Skilled in uncertainty modeling and machine learning approaches, with a notable track record in driving innovation in manufacturing, renewable energy, infrastructure monitoring, and aerospace sectors through interdisciplinary teamwork.

• hazone.me

github.com/lhnguven102

linkedin.com/in/luong-ha-nguyen-697941b4

+1 (438) 928-2616

☑ luongha.nguyen@gmail.com Montreal, QC, CANADA

SKILLS

Languages

Tech Stack

AI/ML

Fluent in English and French, with native proficiency in Vietnamese

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer at AI Redefined | Montreal, QC, CA

July, 2022 - present

- Develop end-to-end machine learning pipelines for time series forecasting and anomaly detection, using reinforcement learning with human feedback to continually enhance accuracy through insights from operators and asset managers.
- Lead the development of vision-based detection algorithms for fault detection.
- Develop cloud-based tools for automating model training, hyperparameter tuning, and model performance tracking.

Applied Research Associate at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

May, 2022 - present

- Lead and coordinate a team of PhDs and postdocs to develop an AI/ML framework, optimizing accuracy and reducing training time in deep neural networks, paving the way for major advancements in various industries.
- Lead the technical development of open-source software for Bayesian neural networks cuTAGI.
- Lead the technical development of Python interface for integration with the C++/CUDA backend.

Machine Learning Engineer at Shearwater Aerospace | Montreal, QC, CA

September, 2021 - June, 2022

- Developed machine learning-based path planning system to improve UAV flight efficiency.
- Developed an autonomous control system using reinforcement learning for UAVs.

Postdoctoral Researcher at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

November, 2019 - September, 2021

- Developed a theory-based approach for modeling uncertainty in deep neural networks, enhancing reliability.
- Develop an open-sourced package BDLM for detecting anomalies in time series.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science for Civil Engineering at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

October, 2019

PERSONAL PROJECTS

cuTAGI for Bayesian Neural Networks (2018-present) | tagiml.com

- cuTAGI: An open-source Bayesian neural network developed in C++/CUDA. It quantifies uncertainty in deep neural networks for various learning tasks, enhancing output reliability and accuracy.

LLM for Finance (2023) | Source code: https://github.com/lhnguyen102/llm-finance

- This project is only for educational and learning purposes, focusing on guiding developers on how to build an LLM model from scratch and then fine-tune it for different tasks.

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Analytically Tractable Hidden-States Inference in Bayesian Neural Networks. Journal to conference track. ICLR.
- 2. Tractable Approximate Gaussian Inference for Bayesian Neural Networks. JMLR, 2021.